{
    "learn-french": {
        "flashcards": [
            {
                "question": "In what year did Queen Victoria choose Ottawa as the Capital of the Province of Canada?",
                "answer": "1857"
            },
            {
                "question": "In what year did Thomas Fuller and Chillion Jones win the design competition for the Original Central Block?",
                "answer": "1859"
            },
            {
                "question": "In what year did James Gladstone became 1st First Nations Senator?",
                "answer": "1958"
            },
            {
                "question": "When was the Centenial Flame lit? ",
                "answer": "1966"
            },
            {
                "question": "The Centenial Flame worked with natural gas up until what year when it was changed to biogas, so it doesnt freeze.",
                "answer": "2021"
            },
            {
                "question": "In what year was the current Canadian Flag hoisted for the first time?",
                "answer": "1965"
            },
            {
                "question": "In what year was the procramation of constitution act 1982 signed, achieving full independence from UK?  ",
                "answer": "1982"
            },
            {
                "question": "In what year was Nelson Mandela welcomed in Canada 4 months after prison release.",
                "answer": "1990"
            },
            {
                "question": "When did the Canadian government took full responsibility for the traumas caused by the residential
school system.",
                "answer": "2008"
            },
            {
                "question": "Which were the first seven provinces? ",
                "answer": "Ontario, Quebec, Nova Scotia, Prince Edward Island, Manitoba, Brittish Columbia, New Brunswick"
            },
            {
                "question": "Which was the last province to join conferation.",
                "answer": "Newfoundland"
            },
            {
                "question": "Which two provinces where amalgated to confederation by PM Wilfred Laurier in 1905 and 1908.",
                "answer": "Alberta, Saskatchewan"
            },
            {
                "question": "What was the purpose of building the Rideau Canal.",
                "answer": "Military"
            },
            {
                "question": "As a result of LT CRL Jhon By designation, what was Ottawas previous name?",
                "answer": "Bytown"
            },
            {
                "question": "In what year did the first member of the house of commons perish",
                "answer": "1868"
            },
            {
                "question": "Who was Henry James Friel",
                "answer": "Pelt Trader and Ottawas Mayor"
            },
            {
                "question": "What does Ottawa mean?",
                "answer": "To trade"
            },
            {
                "question": "What does Rideau mean?",
                "answer": "Courtain"
            },
        
        ]
    }
}